It‘s that time of year when many of us spend money buying gifts for family and friends.
又到了一年中的那个时候，我们中的很多人会花钱给家人和朋友买礼物。
We spend hours, even days, searching the shops and websites trying to find the right present for someone - a pair of socks, perfume, a new gadget - only to find the recipient already has it or they’ve been given it already.
我们花费数小时，甚至数天时间，在商店和网站上搜寻，试图为某人找到合适的礼物——一双袜子、香水、一个新的小玩意儿——结果却发现收礼物的人已经有了，或者别人已经送给他们了。
Or worse, they just don‘t like it, which makes me think, “Are we wasting our time and money?”
更糟糕的是，他们根本不喜欢这份礼物，这让我不禁思考：“我们是在浪费时间和金钱吗？”
There is so much stuff in the world already and so much waste that maybe when it comes to Christmas giving, we need to think outside the box - use our imagination and be more creative with our generosity.
世界上已经有太多的东西和太多的浪费了，所以也许在谈到圣诞节送礼时，我们需要跳出常规思维——发挥我们的想象力，在慷慨解囊时更具创意。
This is particularly true for children, who tend to receive mountains of toys some of which end up not even being looked at.
对于孩子们来说尤其如此，他们往往会收到堆积如山的玩具，其中一些甚至最终都没人看一眼。
One idea is to implement a ’one-gift‘ rule so that children don’t grow up spoiled.
一种想法是实施“一份礼物”规则，以便孩子们不会被宠坏。
Getting too many gifts can also send out the wrong message.
收到太多礼物也可能传递错误的信息。
Speaking to BBC online, clinical psychologist Linda Blair says, “When we are given a lot, we expect to receive a lot... even if it‘s only at Christmas and on birthdays, it will impact on children’s attitudes.”
临床心理学家琳达·布莱尔在接受BBC在线采访时表示：“当我们得到很多东西时，我们就期望得到更多……即使只是在圣诞节和生日时，这也会影响孩子们的态度。”
She also suggests, “If you want to give a gift, give your time”.
她还建议：“如果你想送礼物，就付出你的时间。”
She makes a good point - for children and adults alike, when it comes to giving, think about offering something other than a material object that may get forgotten, discarded or re-gifted.
她提出了一个很好的观点——对于孩子和成年人来说都是如此，在谈到送礼时，考虑送一些别的东西，而不是会被遗忘、丢弃或转赠的物质商品。
Buying an experience is one alternative - a chance for someone to try something out and do something different.
购买一种体验是一种选择——给某人一个尝试新事物和做不同事情的机会。
It will cost you money, but for the recipient it could be an opportunity to try something they could not normally afford or would not have thought about doing.
这会花费你的钱，但对收礼人来说，这可能是一个他们通常负担不起或从未想过要做的尝试。
It would therefore be memorable and, hopefully, much appreciated.
因此，这种尝试将是令人难忘的，并且对方很有可能十分感谢你的好意。
Another practical gift could be to buy someone lessons, giving them a chance to learn new skills such as horse riding or learning English.
另一个实用的礼物可以是爲某人购买课程，给他们一个学习新技能的机会，比如骑马或学英语。
And there are what are called ’favours‘ - money-can’t-buy offerings to do jobs for someone like babysitting, cleaning or giving someone a massage.
还有所谓的“帮忙”——一些用钱买不到的服务，比如照看孩子、打扫卫生或给人按摩。
And there is always the fallback of giving vouchers to spend in a shop.
并且总有后备选项，给购物券让他们在商店里消费。
Of course, if you can‘t think of an original way to give a gift, the alternative is to not buy anything at all.
当然，如果你想不出有创意的送礼方式，另一个选择就是什么都不买。
You may be accused of being a ’Scrooge‘ but at least you’re not wasting money on pointless gifts and you could give the money to charity instead - a more worthy cause.
你可能会被指责为一个“吝啬鬼”，但至少你没有把钱浪费在毫无意义的礼物上，你可以把钱捐给慈善机构——这是一个更有意义的事业。
But if this year, you receive a present that‘s not to your liking don’t be ungrateful and remember the age-old saying that ’it‘s the thought that counts‘.
但是如果今年你收到了一份你不喜欢的礼物，不要不领情，要记住那句古老的谚语：“心意最重要。”